<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 8/20/2011 12:41:33 AM -->
<GameData>
	<!-- English US -->
	<Language_en_US>


		<!-- +++++++++++++ -->
		<!-- +  NATIONS  + -->
		<!-- +++++++++++++ -->


		<!-- FRANCE -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_WWII_FRANCE">
			<Text>French Republic</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_WWII_FRANCE_SHORT">
			<Text>France</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_EURO1940_FRANCE_BRIEFING">
			<Text>
				General, France has been the center of the world of culture and arts for centuries, we are one of the few countries to be a standing Democracy and our military stands as the most modernized in the world. After the Great War ("La Der des Ders" as we thougth then) our nation had to rebuild herself, but just after we were plunged into the world depression and now things get worse as acts of agression increase in Europe and the Pacific. Now the world looks to our power to counter the rise of facism and the ideals of militarism.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As peace is more and more uncertain, the people of France have chosen you to be their leader in these hard times. Can you General lead France to repel the Facist agression, can you make this war to come to truly be "the Last of the Last" ?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Army:[/COLOR]                      [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_CITY_BLUE]Navy:[/COLOR]                      [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_RESEARCH_RATE]Air Force:[/COLOR]                [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_YIELD_GOLD]Economy:[/COLOR]                 [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_YIELD_PRODUCTION]Production:[/COLOR]              [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_CULTURE_RATE]Diplomatic Situation:[/COLOR] [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL]
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_FRANCE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Invasion</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_FRANCE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				The Invasion of Poland caused France and Britain to declare war against Germany. But the Allies did not launch massive assaults and kept a defensive stance: this was called the Phoney War in Britain or Drôle de guerre—the funny sort of war—in France. It did not prevent the German army from conquering Poland in a matter of weeks with its innovative Blitzkrieg tactics and helped by the Soviet Union's attack on Poland. When Germany had its hands free for an attack in the west, the Battle of France began in May 1940, and the same tactics proved just as devastating there. The Wehrmacht bypassed the Maginot Line by marching through the Ardennes forest. A second German force was sent into Belgium and the Netherlands to act as a diversion to this main thrust. In six weeks of savage fighting the French lost 90,000 men. Many civilians sought refuge by taking to the roads of France: some two million refugees from Belgium and Holland were joined by between eight and ten million French civilians, representing a quarter of the French population, all heading south and west. This movement may well have been the largest single movement of civilians in history prior to 1947.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_FRANCE_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Occupation</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_FRANCE_TEXT_2">
			<Text>
				French leaders surrendered to Nazi Germany on 24 June 1940, after the British Expeditionary Force was evacuated from Dunkirk. Nazi Germany occupied three fifths of France's territory, leaving the rest in the southeast to the new Vichy government. This regime sought to collaborate with Germany. It was established on 10 July 1940. The Vichy Regime was led by Philippe Pétain, the aging war hero of First World war. It was originally intended to be a temporary, care-taker regime, to supervise French administration before the soon-expected defeat of Britain. Instead, it lasted four years. It was unique among the various collaborating regimes of wartime Europe in that it was established constitutionally, through the French parliament. However, Charles de Gaulle declared himself on Radio Londres the head of a rival government in exile, gathering the Free French Forces around him, finding support in some French colonies and recognition from Britain and the USA.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				The Vichy regime adopted violent, repressive anti-semitic policies on its own initiative, without direction from Nazi Germany. During the German occupation 76,000 Jews would be deported, often with the help of the Vichy French authorities, and murdered in the Nazis' extermination camps. After the Attack on Mers-el-Kébir in 1940, where the British fleet destroyed a large part of the French navy, still under command of Vichy France, that killed about 1,100 sailors, there was nationwide indignation and a feeling of distrust in the French forces, leading to the events of the Battle of Dakar. Eventually, several important French ships such as the Richelieu and the Surcouf joined the Free French Forces. On the Eastern Front the USSR was lacking pilots and several French pilots joined the Soviet Union and fought the Luftwaffe in the Normandie-Niemen squadron. Within France proper, very few people organized themselves against the German Occupation in the summer of 1940. However, their numbers grew as the Vichy regime resorted to more strident policies in order to fulfill the enormous demands of the Nazis and the eventual decline of Nazi Germany became more obvious. Isolated opposers eventually formed a real movement: the Resistance. There were also Frenchmen who joined the SS, they were known as the Charlemagne Division; knowing they would not survive should Germany be defeated, they were among the last ones to surrender at Berlin.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				In November 1942 Vichy France was finally occupied by German forces, because the war in North Africa was coming to an end; the Germans foresaw a threat in southern Europe by the allied forces.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_FRANCE_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Liberation</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_FRANCE_TEXT_3">
			<Text>
				On 6 June 1944 the Allies landed in Normandy while on 15 August they landed in Provence (including the 260,000 men of the French army B). General Leclerc freed Paris and Strasbourg and later, along with the battleship Richelieu, represented France at Tokyo during the Japanese surrender.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- GERMANY -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_WWII_GERMANY">
			<Text>German Reich</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_WWII_GERMANY_SHORT">
			<Text>Germany</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_EURO1940_GERMANY_BRIEFING">
			<Text>
				Mein Führer, After World War I, we were humiliated by the betrayal of our own leaders and treated harshly by the Treaty of Versaille. The Weimer Republic has failed and has driven us into economic disaster. After turmoil and bad leadership, you have finally risen to power. Already you have turned our country around into a new glorious empire, The Third Reich, by defying the Treaty of Versaille and solving Germany's economic issues.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Fatherland has always been a great nation, our military the best in the world, our generals unmatched and our industrial might unseen. Mein Führer, can you lead the German People to complete world domination, can you give them "das tausendjährige Reich" you've promised ?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Army:[/COLOR]                      [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_CITY_BLUE]Navy:[/COLOR]                      [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_RESEARCH_RATE]Air Force:[/COLOR]                [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_YIELD_GOLD]Economy:[/COLOR]                 [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_YIELD_PRODUCTION]Production:[/COLOR]              [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_CULTURE_RATE]Diplomatic Situation:[/COLOR] [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL]
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_GERMANY_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_GERMANY_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				In 1935, Germany reacquired control of the Saar and in 1936 military control of the Rhineland, both of which had been lost in the Treaty of Versailles. In 1938 and 1939, Austria and Czechoslovakia were brought under German control and the invasion of Poland was prepared through the Molotov–Ribbentrop pact and Operation Himmler. On 1 September 1939 the German Wehrmacht launched a blitzkrieg on Poland, which was swiftly occupied by Germany and by the Soviet Red Army. The UK and France declared war on Germany, marking the beginning of World War II.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				As the war progressed, Germany and its allies quickly gained control of much of continental Europe while the plan to occupy the United Kingdom failed. On 22 June 1941, Germany broke the Molotov–Ribbentrop pact and invaded the Soviet Union. The same year, Japan attacked the American base at Pearl Harbor, and Germany declared war on the United States. The Battle of Stalingrad forced the German army to retreat on the Eastern front. In September 1943, Germany's ally Italy surrendered, and German troops were forced to defend an additional front in Italy. D-Day opened a Western front, as Allied forces advanced towards German territory. On 8 May 1945, the German armed forces surrendered after the Red Army occupied Berlin.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- UK -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_WWII_UK">
			<Text>United Kingdom</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_WWII_UK_SHORT">
			<Text>U.K.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_EURO1940_UK_BRIEFING">
			<Text>
				Prime Minister, the British Empire has been the largest and most powerful on the face of the earth for centuries. We have been the protector of Democracy and the leading humitarian country of the world, our military might has gone unmatched for a long time. But many nations have grown up to challenge what we stand for and what we see right. The costly victory during World War I and the depression the world has slipped into has tremendously damaged our great economy.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]However the people have elected you as the war menace is growing in Europe, relying on your leadership and strength to stand up against militarism and facism. Can you Prime Minister defeat the aggressors and get us out of this depression, can you prevent the fall of our Empire against all odds ?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Army:[/COLOR]                      [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_CITY_BLUE]Navy:[/COLOR]                      [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_RESEARCH_RATE]Air Force:[/COLOR]                [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_YIELD_GOLD]Economy:[/COLOR]                 [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_YIELD_PRODUCTION]Production:[/COLOR]              [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_CULTURE_RATE]Diplomatic Situation:[/COLOR] [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL]
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_UK_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_UK_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The United Kingdom, along with the British Empire's crown colonies, especially British India, declared war on Nazi Germany in 1939, after the German invasion of Poland. Hostilities with Japan began in 1941, after it attacked British colonies in Asia. Following the defeat of its European allies, in the first year of the war, the United Kingdom continued the fight against Germany which took form with notable periods such as the Battle of Britain and the Battle of the Atlantic. Following the D-Day landings and the subsequent defeat of Germany and her allies, the UK was one of the "Big Three" that met at the end of the war to plan the postwar world. The war left the United Kingdom financially damaged although aid from the Marshall Plan and loans taken from both the United States and Canada helped the UK on the road to recovery.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- ITALY -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_WWII_ITALY">
			<Text>Italy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_WWII_ITALY_SHORT">
			<Text>Italy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_EURO1940_ITALY_BRIEFING">
			<Text>
				Duce, After the costly victory during World War I, our government went into turmoil and fearing a Communist uprising they installed you to power. Taking immediate action, you have eliminated all opposition and have becomed the first Fascist leader in Europe. The people of Italy have gotten weary of your rule and are upset by the hard economic times that have come upon them, however you have promised them a New Roman empire and defying the League of Nations you have already invaded Eithopia, first to fall under our domination.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]For centuries we were the most important empire in the West and the hard working Italian people look to you to establish back their glory. Duce, can you restore a powerful Empire, can you make Rome the center of the world once again ?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Army:[/COLOR]                      [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_CITY_BLUE]Navy:[/COLOR]                      [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_RESEARCH_RATE]Air Force:[/COLOR]                [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_YIELD_GOLD]Economy:[/COLOR]                 [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_YIELD_PRODUCTION]Production:[/COLOR]              [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_CULTURE_RATE]Diplomatic Situation:[/COLOR] [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL]
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_ITALY_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_ITALY_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				In 1935, Mussolini invaded Ethiopia, resulting in an international alienation and leading to Italy's withdrawal from the League of Nations. Consequently, Italy allied with Nazi Germany and Empire of Japan and strongly supported Franco in the Spanish civil war. In 1939, Italy occupied Albania, a de facto protectorate for decades, and entered World War II in 1940 on the side of the Axis powers. Mussolini, wanting a quick victory like Hitler's Blitzkriegs in Poland and France, invaded Greece in October 1940 but was forced to accept a humiliating stalemate after a few months. At the same time, Italy, after initially conquering British Somalia and parts of Egypt, saw an allied counter-attack lead to the loss of all possessions in the Horn of Africa and in North Africa.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				Italy was then invaded by the Allies in July 1943, leading to the collapse of the Fascist regime and the fall of Mussolini. In September 1943, Italy surrendered. The country remained a battlefield for the rest of the war, as the allies were moving up from the south as the north was the base for loyalist Italian fascist and German Nazi forces, fought also by the Italian resistance movement.The hostilities ended on 2 May 1945. Nearly half a million Italians (including civilians) died in the conflict, and the Italian economy had been all but destroyed; per capita income in 1944 was at its lowest point since the beginning of the 20th century.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- USSR -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_WWII_USSR">
			<Text>U.S.S.R.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_WWII_USSR_SHORT">
			<Text>U.S.S.R.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_EURO1940_USSR_BRIEFING">
			<Text>
				Comrade, long have the people of the world been cursed by Imperialism and Capitalism. But no longer, the glorious Soviet Union has risen out of the ashes of the horrible World War I and the Great October Revolution. However our nation has now to defeat Facism and the evil influences of the West to become the superpower it is meant to be.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The people of the glorious Soviet Union have recognized you as the absolute authority to lead them to victory against the capitalist and fascist menace. Can you comrade show the world the power of our socialist government, spreading our communist ideals all over the world, can you make us the true victorious power of the war to come ?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Army:[/COLOR]                      [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_CITY_BLUE]Navy:[/COLOR]                      [ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_RESEARCH_RATE]Air Force:[/COLOR]                [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_YIELD_GOLD]Economy:[/COLOR]                 [ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_YIELD_PRODUCTION]Production:[/COLOR]              [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_CULTURE_RATE]Diplomatic Situation:[/COLOR] [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL]
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_USSR_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_USSR_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				In 1938, after the United Kingdom and France had concluded the Munich Agreement with Germany, the USSR dealt with the Nazis as well, both militarily and economically during extensive talks. The two countries concluded the German–Soviet Nonaggression Pact and the German–Soviet Commercial Agreement. The nonaggression pact made possible Soviet occupation of Lithuania, Latvia, Estonia, Bessarabia, northern Bukovina, and eastern Poland. In late November of the same year, unable to coerce the Republic of Finland by diplomatic means into moving its border 25 kilometres (16 mi) back from Leningrad, Joseph Stalin ordered the invasion of Finland.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				In the east, the Soviet military won several decisive victories during border clashes with the Japanese Empire in 1938 and 1939. However, in April 1941, USSR signed the Soviet–Japanese Neutrality Pact with the Empire of Japan, recognizing the territorial integrity of Manchukuo, a Japanese puppet state.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				Although it has been debated whether the Soviet Union had any intention of invading Germany once it was strong enough, Germany itself broke the treaty and invaded the Soviet Union on 22 June 1941, starting what was known in the USSR as the "Great Patriotic War". The Red Army stopped the seemingly-invincible German Army at the Battle of Moscow, aided by an unusually harsh winter. The Battle of Stalingrad, which lasted from late 1942 to early 1943, dealt a severe blow to the Germans from which they never fully recovered and became a turning point of the war. After Stalingrad, Soviet forces drove through Eastern Europe to Berlin before Germany surrendered in 1945.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				The same year, the USSR, in fulfillment of its agreement with the Allies at the Yalta Conference, denounced the Soviet–Japanese Neutrality Pact in April 1945 and invaded Manchukuo and other Japan-controlled territories on 9 August 1945. This conflict ended with a decisive Soviet victory, contributing to the unconditional surrender of Japan and the end of World War II.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- GREECE -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_WWII_GREECE">
			<Text>Greece</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_WWII_GREECE_SHORT">
			<Text>Greece</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RED_EURO1940_GREECE_BRIEFING">
			<Text>
				Arkhigos Metaxas, Hellas lives dark days, we are the fathers of the western civilization and now after more than 10,000 years of existance our country is under one of the biggest threat it has known. The first world war has left deep wounds in every aspect of our nation, our army equipment is obsolete, and none of our frontiers is safe. But the Hellines never learned the word "surrender", our defenders won't be our guns but the well know courage and honor of the Hellenic armies who have protected our nation for all these centuries. Metaxas, the sons of the Spartans and Alexander the Great are waiting for you to lead them, but will it be to victory or to a honorable death, to another Marathon or to another Thermopylae ?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Army:[/COLOR]                      [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_CITY_BLUE]Navy:[/COLOR]                      [ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_RESEARCH_RATE]Air Force:[/COLOR]                [ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_YIELD_GOLD]Economy:[/COLOR]                 [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_YIELD_PRODUCTION]Production:[/COLOR]              [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_CULTURE_RATE]Diplomatic Situation:[/COLOR] [ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL][ICON_CAPITAL]
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_GREECE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WW2_SCENARIO_CIV_GREECE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Despite the country's numerically small and ill-equipped armed forces, Greece made a decisive contribution to the Allied efforts in World War II. At the start of the war Greece sided with the Allies and refused to give in to Mussolini ultimatum demanding occupation rights to strategic Greek sites. When the Italian envoy presented these demands on 28 October 1940 to the Greek prime Minister Metaxas, he was met with a curt reply: "Alors, c'est la guerre" ("then it is war"). Italy invaded Greece by way of Albania on 28 October 1940, but Greek troops repelled the invaders after a bitter struggle. This marked the first Allied victory in the war.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				Primarily to secure his strategic southern flank, German dictator Adolf Hitler reluctantly stepped in and launched the Battle of Greece. Troops from Germany, Bulgaria, and Italy successfully invaded Greece, through Yugoslavia, overcoming Greek, British, Australian, and New Zealand units.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				On 20 May 1941, the Germans attempted to seize Crete with a large attack by paratroops—with the aim of reducing the threat of a counter-offensive by Allied forces in Egypt—but faced heavy resistance. The Greek campaign might have delayed German military plans against Soviet Union and the heavy losses of German paratroopers led the Germans to launch no further large-scale air-invasions.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				During the years of Occupation of Greece by Nazi Germany, thousands of Greeks died in direct combat, in concentration camps, or of starvation. The occupiers murdered the greater part of the Jewish community despite efforts by the Greek Orthodox Church and many other Christian Greeks to shelter the Jews. The economy of Greece was devastated.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				When the Soviet Army began its drive across Romania in August 1944, the German Army in Greece began withdrawing north and northwestward from Greece into Yugoslavia and Albania to avoid being cut off in Greece. Hence, the German occupation of Greece ended in October 1944. British troops landed on 4 October in Patras, and entered Athens at October 13.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				During the period between 1942 and 1944, known as the first phase of the greek civil wars, marxist and non-Marxist resistance groups fought each other in a fratricidal conflict to establish the leadership of the Greek resistance movement. In the second phase (1944) the ascendant communists, in military control of most of Greece, confronted the returning Greek government in exile, which had been formed under Western Allied auspices in Cairo and originally included six KKE-affiliated ministers. In the third phase (commonly called the "Third Round" by the Communists) (1946–1949), guerrilla forces controlled by KKE fought against the internationally recognized Greek Government which was formed after elections boycotted by KKE.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				The civil war left Greece with a legacy of political polarization; as a result, Greece also entered into alliance with the United States and joined NATO, while relationships with its Communist northern neighbours, both pro-Soviet and neutral, became strained.
			</Text>
		</Row>


		<!-- +++++++++++++ -->
		<!-- +  LEADERS  + -->
		<!-- +++++++++++++ -->

		<!-- DE GAULLE -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_DE_GAULLE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_DE_GAULLE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				A veteran of World War I, in the 1920s and 1930s de Gaulle came to the fore as a proponent of mobile armoured divisions, which he considered would become central in modern warfare. During World War II, he reached the temporary rank of Brigadier General, leading one of the few successful armoured counter-attacks during the 1940 Battle of France, and then briefly served in the French government as France was falling.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				He escaped to Britain and gave a famous radio address, broadcast by the BBC on 18 June 1940, exhorting the French people to resist Nazi Germany and organised the Free French Forces with exiled French officers in Britain.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				He gradually obtained control of all French colonies except Indochina—most of which had at first been controlled by the pro-German Vichy regime—and by the time of the liberation of France in 1944 he was heading a government in exile, insisting that France be treated as an independent great power by the other Allies. De Gaulle became prime minister in the French Provisional Government, resigning in 1946 due to political conflicts.('from Wikipedia')
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_DE_GAULLE_LIVED">
			<Text>1890 - 1970 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_DE_GAULLE_NAME">
			<Text>Charles De Gaulle</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_DE_GAULLE_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Chef des Forces Françaises</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_DE_GAULLE">
			<Text>Charles De Gaulle</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- HITLER -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_HITLER_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_HITLER_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Adolf Hitler was an Austrian-born German politician and the leader of the National Socialist German Workers Party, commonly known as the Nazi Party. He was Chancellor of Germany from 1933 to 1945 and, after 1934, also head of state as Führer und Reichskanzler, ruling the country as an absolute dictator.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				A decorated veteran of World War I, Hitler joined the precursor of the Nazi Party (NSDAP) in 1919 and became leader of NSDAP in 1921. He attempted a failed coup called the Beer Hall Putsch in Munich in 1923, for which he was imprisoned. Following his imprisonment, in which he wrote Mein Kampf, he gained support by promoting German nationalism, anti-semitism, anti-capitalism, and anti-communism with charismatic oratory and propaganda. He was appointed chancellor in 1933, and quickly transformed the Weimar Republic into the Third Reich, a single-party dictatorship based on the totalitarian and autocratic ideals of national socialism.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				Hitler ultimately wanted to establish a New Order of absolute Nazi German hegemony in continental Europe. To achieve this, he pursued a foreign policy with the declared goal of seizing Lebensraum for the Aryan people; directing the resources of the state towards this goal. This included the rearmament of Germany, which culminated in 1939 when the Wehrmacht invaded Poland. In response, the United Kingdom and France declared war against Germany, leading to the outbreak of World War II in Europe.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				Within three years, Germany and the Axis powers had occupied most of Europe, and most of Northern Africa, East and Southeast Asia and the Pacific Ocean. However, with the reversal of the Nazi invasion of the Soviet Union, the Allies gained the upper hand from 1942 onwards. By 1945, Allied armies had invaded German-held Europe from all sides. Nazi forces engaged in numerous violent acts during the war, including the systematic murder of as many as 17 million civilians, including an estimated six million Jews targeted in the Holocaust and between 500,000 and 1,500,000 Roma, Poles, Soviet civilians, Soviet prisoners of war, people with disabilities, homosexuals, Jehovah's Witnesses, and other political and religious opponents.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				In the final days of the war, during the Battle of Berlin in 1945, Hitler married his long-time mistress Eva Braun and, to avoid capture by Soviet forces less than two days later, the two committed suicide on 30 April 1945. ('from Wikipedia')
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_HITLER_LIVED">
			<Text>1889 - 1945 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_HITLER_NAME">
			<Text>Adolf Hitler</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_HITLER_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Führer of the Third Reich</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_HITLER">
			<Text>Adolf Hitler</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- CHURCHILL -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CHURCHILL_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CHURCHILL_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Sir Winston Leonard Spencer-Churchill, (30 November 1874 - 24 January 1965) was a British politician and statesman known for his leadership of the United Kingdom during the Second World War. He is widely regarded as one of the great wartime leaders. He served as Prime Minister twice (1940–45 and 1951–55). A noted statesman and orator, Churchill was also an officer in the British Army, a historian, a writer, and an artist. To date, he is the only British prime minister to have received the Nobel Prize in Literature, and he was the first person to be made an honorary citizen of the United States. ('from Wikipedia')
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CHURCHILL_LIVED">
			<Text>1874 - 1965 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CHURCHILL_NAME">
			<Text>Winston Churchill</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CHURCHILL_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Prime Minister of UK</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_CHURCHILL">
			<Text>Winston Churchill</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- MUSSOLINI -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MUSSOLINI_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MUSSOLINI_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Mussolini became the 40th Prime Minister of Italy in 1922 and began using the title Il Duce by 1925. After 1936, his official title was "His Excellency Benito Mussolini, Head of Government, Duce of Fascism, and Founder of the Empire". Mussolini also created and held the supreme military rank of First Marshal of the Empire along with King Victor Emmanuel III of Italy, which gave him and the King joint supreme control over the military of Italy. Mussolini remained in power until he was replaced in 1943; for a short period after this until his death, he was the leader of the Italian Social Republic.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				Mussolini was among the founders of Italian Fascism, which included elements of nationalism, corporatism, national syndicalism, expansionism, social progress, and anti-socialism in combination with censorship of subversives and state propaganda. In the years following his creation of the Fascist ideology, Mussolini influenced, or achieved admiration from, a wide variety of political figures. ('from Wikipedia')
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MUSSOLINI_LIVED">
			<Text>1883 - 1945 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MUSSOLINI_NAME">
			<Text>Benito Mussolini</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_MUSSOLINI_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Duce of Italy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_MUSSOLINI">
			<Text>Benito Mussolini</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- STALIN -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_STALIN_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_STALIN_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Joseph Vissarionovich Stalin (18 December 1878 - 5 March 1953) was a Georgian-born, Soviet politician and Bolshevik revolutionary, who held the position of first General Secretary of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union's Central Committee from 1922 until his death in 1953. While formally the office of the General Secretary was elective and was not initially regarded as the top position in the Soviet state, after Vladimir Lenin's death in 1924, Stalin managed to consolidate more and more power in his hands, gradually putting down all opposition groups within the party. This included Leon Trotsky, the Red Army organizer, proponent of world revolution, and principal critic of Stalin among the early Soviet leaders, who was exiled from the Soviet Union in 1929. Instead, Stalin's idea of socialism in one country became the primary line of the Soviet politics. ('from Wikipedia')
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_STALIN_LIVED">
			<Text>1878 - 1953 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_STALIN_NAME">
			<Text>Joseph Stalin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_STALIN_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>General Secretary of the Communist Party</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_STALIN">
			<Text>Joseph Stalin</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- METAXAS -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_METAXAS_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_METAXAS_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Born in 1871 in Ithaki, Ioannis Metaxas was a high army officer who in 1936 was appointed prime minister by the king George II and later on took total power, saving Greece from an economic collapse and successfully equipping 800,000 troops instead of the 200,000 Greece could arm before him. He also achieved to unit the divided Hellenic people under his dictatorship and led them to great victories against the axis. Metaxas died in Athens on January 29, 1941 from a toxaemia, before the German invasion of Greece.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_METAXAS_LIVED">
			<Text>1871 - 1941 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_METAXAS_NAME">
			<Text>Ioannis Metaxas</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_METAXAS_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Arkhigos of Hellas</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_METAXAS">
			<Text>Ioannis Metaxas</Text>
		</Row>


	</Language_en_US>

	<!-- German -->
	<Language_DE_DE>
	</Language_DE_DE>
	<!-- Spanish -->
	<Language_ES_ES>
	</Language_ES_ES>
	<!-- French -->
	<Language_FR_FR>
	</Language_FR_FR>
	<!-- Italian -->
	<Language_IT_IT>
	</Language_IT_IT>

</GameData>